

RAFIUL BARI ANGAN

Date of birth: 26/07/1998 **Nationality:** Bangladeshi | **Gender:** Male

(+880) 01781781680 | <u>rafiulangan@gmail.com</u>

70/1 Kazikanda, 7700, Rajbari, Bangladesh

About me:

I am passionate about pursuing a career as a civil engineer, both academically and professionally. I can place my skills and techniques to excellent use in a specialized environment, where I can make a significant contribution to both individual and group accomplishments while also improving my strategies and capabilities in the same field.

WORK EXPERIENCE

10/06/2020 – 10/07/2021 – Dhaka, Bangladesh CIVIL SAFETY ASSESSOR – SAFETY CONSULTANTS BD

- · Structural and Architectural drawing of buildings and site investigation.
- · Conducting Non-Destructive Tests and prepared assessments reports of those buildings.
- Quality analysis of NDT reports.
- · Operate Ferro-scanner, UPV machine, and Rebound Hammer.

13/02/2019 - 12/03/2019 - Dhaka, Bangladesh

INTERN ENGINEER - THE STRUCTURAL ENGINEERS LTD.

The authorities and project coordinator taught me various types of construction methods. Slab casting, pile casting, and column-beam casting were among the techniques I learned. I was also informed about the various types of construction materials as well as various safety precautions. I also learned how to plot all of my drawings and solve numerous challenges.

Construction info@sel.com.bd http://sel.com.bd/Default.aspx

SEL Center, 29, West Panthapath, Bir Uttam Kazi Nuruzzamam Road, 1205, Dhaka, Bangladesh

01/01/2019 - 10/02/2019 - Natore, Bangladesh

INTERN ENGINEER - M. I. CEMENT FACTORY LTD.

I learned about the chemical ingredients used in cement as well as the manufacturing process. I also conducted a field survey. I've worked with a variety of construction companies when it comes to seals. In addition, I learned about the supply and demand for cement on the market.

Manufacturing | info@crowncement.com | https://crowncement.com/

Delta Life Tower, Plot 37 Rd 90, 1212, Dhaka, Bangladesh

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

06/03/2016 - 16/03/2020 - Qadirabad Cantonment, Natore, Rajshahi, Bangladesh

B.SC. IN CIVIL ENGINEERING - Bangladesh Army University of Engineering & Technology (BAUET), Bangladesh

Engineering Mechanics, Engineering Materials, Engineering Geology and Geomorphology, Mechanics of Solids I and II, Fluid Mechanics, Structural Analysis and Design I and II, Design of Concrete Structures I and II, Environmental Engineering I and II, Principles of Soil Mechanics, Design of Steel Structures, Transportation Engineering I, II, III, IV and V, Open Channel Flow, Foundation Engineering, Steel-Concrete Composite Structures, Pre-stressed Concrete. **Field(s) of study**

Civil Engineering

Thesis: Effect of corrosion on mechanical properties of TMT bars

3.76 out of 4 | EQF level 6 | Bachelor of Science | BD Credit Hours | 163 | https://bauet.ac.bd/

2013 – 2015 – College Para, Binodpur, Rajbari, Bangladesh

HSC - Rajbari Government College, Rajbari, Bangladesh

Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry, and Biology

4.58 out of 5.00 | EQF level 4 | Higher Secondary Certificate | https://rajbarigovtcollege.edu.bd/

2008 – 2013 – Rajbari Sadar, Rajbari, Bangladesh **SSC** – Rajbari Govt. High School, Rajbari, Bangladesh

Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry, Computer

4.50 out of 5.00 | EQF level 3 | Secondary School Certificate

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **BENGALI**

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production Spoken interaction		
ENGLISH	C1	B2	B2	B2	B2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

ETABS AND SAFE AutoCAD ArcGIS C/C++ Microsoft Excel & PowerPoint

PROJECTS

01/03/2019 - 01/03/2020

Construction of 2 Class room Academic Building with 4-Storied Foundation including Sanitary

It was a practice test of a real-life project. Using the knowledge and techniques gained from our research, the project was replicated. Field surveys and soil tests were simulated. The plan layout was then created using AutoCAD. I developed an ETABS model of that project based on our national building code. I also created a bill of quantity (BOQ) after analyzing the model. Finally, I turn the project over to the authorities.

CONFERENCES AND SEMINARS

2020 – Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology, Dhaka, 1000, Bangladesh **Structural Engineering**

2019 – Bangladesh Army University of Engineering & Technology (BAUET), QC, Natore, Bangladesh Business Research on Brand Equity

2018 – Bangladesh Army University of Engineering & Technology (BAUET), QC, Natore, Bangladesh Water Resource and Management

2016 – Bangladesh Army University of Engineering & Technology (BAUET), QC, Natore, Bangladesh Uses of Paints and Paint Quality

HONOURS AND AWARDS

2020

Student scholarship-2020 - Bangladesh Army University of Engineering & Technology

2018

Student scholarship-2018 - Bangladesh Army University of Engineering & Technology

2020

 $Selected for 2nd \,Round \,of \,GPH is path-Prothom \,Alo\, ''En-Genius \,Structural \,Engineering \,Competition'' \,2020-Bangladesh \,University \,of \,Engineering \,and \,Technology$

2015

Second Runners-up (Regional Math Olympiad) - Bangladesh Mathematical Olympiad

2010

Bronze Medal-7th International Children Art Competition – Bangladesh Shilpokola Academy

MANAGEMENT AND LEADERSHIP SKILLS

Mentor- Rajbari Career Club (2021-Present)

General Sectary- BAUET Debating Club (2019-2020)

Organization Sectary- BAUET Career Club (2018-2020)

Office Sectary- BAUET Photography and Media Club (2018-2020)

VOLUNTEERING

CURRENT

Foods & Cloths among Flood Affected People

2017 - 2020

Warm Clothes give away for the needy people

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Traveling

https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC7j_7KJj1x8cEIRFZwBCFaQ

Photo & Videography

https://www.facebook.com/Angans-Notebook-106444191513412

Drawings & Paintings

RECOMMENDATIONS

Dr. Mahmudur Rahaman – Assistant Professor – <u>drmahmudur.rits@gmail.com</u>

Dependent of Civil Engineering, Bangladesh Army University of Engineering & Technology, QC, Natore, Bangladesh

 $Md.\ Mohasin\ Ali-Thesis\ Supervisor-\underline{mmali19bd@gmail.com}$

Senior Lecturer, Dependent of Civil Engineering, Bangladesh Army University of Engineering & Technology, QC, Natore, Bangladesh